

# NICHOLAS FREBERG

nfreberg@student.bridgew.edu
101 Wales Street Abington, MA 02351
781-361-0203 (Mobile)
Professional References Are in Original Application

# **OBJECTIVES**

I am a 21-year-old student at Bridgewater State University, entering my senior year. Currently, I work over in Bridgewater looking for an opportunity to set a foundation for a professional career in the field of Information Technology (Specifically in Networking/Telecommunications or security), where I can apply the skills and knowledge that I've gained as a Computer Science major. I am a team player who wants to see myself and those around me succeed. I am seeking a position that will give me the opportunity to blend together my passion for technology, my boundless imagination, and my innate desire to help others.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BRIDGEWATER STATE UNIVERSITY**

May 2020: Bachelor's Degree in Science

- Major: Computer Science, No concentration
- Unofficial Academic Transcript Available upon request
- As of April 2019: Cumulative GPA of 2.901

# **EXPERIENCE**

# CVS/PHARMACY | 1504 Main Street S. Weymouth, MA

#### CLERK/CASHIER MARCH 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2018

- Working behind cash register for extended periods of time
- Process photo orders at Kodak photo kiosk
- Putting up and taking down sale signs at the end of every week
- Scan in vendors & take inventory of what our store has in stock
- Unload weekly truck shipments and fill stock shelves
- Keeping store clean and organized
- Happily offer all-star level customer service

#### SHIFT SUPERVISOR/RX SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

- Opening and Closing Store
- Provide the best customer service
- Responsible for keeping store clean
- Checking in vendors and making orders for the store
- Stocking Shelves
- Unloading Weekly deliveries

- Training New Employees
- Assisting in Photo Department as needed
- Take Passport Pictures
- Price Changes & putting up weekly sale signs
- Process customer transactions and returns
- Cycle Counts to check for product accuracy
- Processing Damages
- Counting money
- Act as a cashier as needed
- Work in prescription production
- Fill prescriptions in a timely manner
- Assist customers in picking up and dropping off prescriptions
- Make phone calls to patients to inquire about prescriptions

# BRIDGEWATER STATE UNIVERSITY | 131 Summer Street Bridgewater, MA

#### **RESNET SUPPORT REPRESENTATIVE SEPTEMBER 2018 – PRESENT**

- Advertised the University's resident services (Cable TV, Wireless Internet, WEPA printers, telephone service, Netflix, Hulu, HBO and Xfinity On Campus) to our students
- Answered phone calls from students, faculty, and families to answer questions about our services
- Entered and managed tickets for service requests in TeamDynamix
- Made appointments to meet with students regarding their ticket to resolve the problem
- Installed DTA TV boxes in students' dorms if their Televisions were having issues
- Walked students through how to do certain tasks (Running a TV Channel Scan, connecting to our wireless networks, etc.)
- Became familiar with Cisco telecommunication systems (troubleshooting access points, configuring switches and individual switchports)
- Carried out administrative tasks when the need arose
- Used Skype for Business, Outlook and Amazon Echo Show to communicate with colleagues
- Maintained and kept inventory on WEPA printer kiosks campus-wide
- Went above and beyond when providing customer service for every customer
- Update ResNet website and social media (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram)
- Maintained media devices in residence hall lounges (Amazon Firesticks, Smart TVs)
- Enter TeamDynamix tickets to ensure appropriate and prompt solutions to resident students
- Assist in creating marketing information for resident students via new student orientations,
   ResNet promotion nights, social media, digital signage

# **SKILLS**

- Fluent in the following programming languages: Python, Java, C++, C, Go, Rust, F#
- Experience working with Cisco Networking equipment (Wired and Wireless)
- Office 365 Suite and Skype for Business experience
- Knowledge and experience working with Unix (Via different Linux kernels i.e. Ubuntu, Fedora)
- Knowledge of Mac and Windows operating systems
- Currently Working Towards CCENT Certification; In the future will go for CCNA Security Cert.

- Working knowledge of the OSI model and each of its layers
- Working knowledge of Fluke Networks equipment (Aircheck, Fluke and Toner, DTX, H30)
- Fast learner
- Able to provide detailed documentation about work done
- Enthusiastic about networking and cybersecurity

#### NOTEWORTHY ACHIEVEMENTS

- As a student worker for Bridgewater State University's ResNet department, I assisted the University's Networking team with their Network Infrastructure update in Winter 2019 (Installing and configuring Cisco switches, troubleshooting dissociated APs, installing new UPS units, creating port maps, etc.)
- As an attempt to streamline my workflow at ResNet, I created an HTML scraper program in Python
  that would read from our Wepa printer status page and would alert me which printers on campus
  needed attention.
- Participated in a focus group regarding Bridgewater State University's mobile app, where I gave my
  feedback on both the current design and the prototype design of the app
- Have built multiple desktop PCs and have a working knowledge of all their components
- Created a server/client program in Java that simulates propagation delay, packet loss and RTT
- Created a simple C++ Text-Based Adventure Game (available upon request)
- Created a chat server program in the Go programming language
- At the time of this resume's most recent edit, I am working on a Wireless Networks project that will take class attendance via the use of RFID tags and a Raspberry Pi 3 B+

# PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Christina Gill (ResNet Support Specialist/Supervisor)

C5Gill@bridgew.edu

508.531.3422 (Office Phone)

Mary O'Neill (ResNet Manager)

MOneill@bridgew.edu

508.531.1004 (Office Phone)

Travis Rebello (Network Administrator @ Bridgewater State University)

T3Rebello@bridgew.edu

508.531.7464 (Office Phone)